<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Christopher Lee Murray]]></title><description><![CDATA[~/think/interlink/ink/_]]></description><link>https://iamthinkking.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 16:03:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamthinkking.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Fedora25: Synapse and Your Display Server]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_problem">The Problem</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of the tools I&#8217;ve constantly used when on a Linux distribution is <a href="https://launchpad.net/synapse-project">Synapse</a>. It&#8217;s a really fast application launcher. I&#8217;ve tried <a href="https://github.com/ManuelSchneid3r/albert">albert</a> and others but none have pleased me as much. Since I switched to Fedora25 back in December 2016, I&#8217;ve been using GNOME&#8217;s built in search which resides in the dashboard. It suffices but the rendering required can cause it to be a bit laggy when resources are being hogged (especially by Chome 😢). So I&#8217;ve decided to install Synapse. Unfortunately after installing, it wouldn&#8217;t launch from the application menu. I opened Terminix and typed <code>synapse</code> only to see it crash from a segmentation fault 🤐. I decided to Google search the issue and came across these links:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://ask.fedoraproject.org/en/question/98598/i-get-a-segmentation-fault-when-starting-synapse-on-fedora-25-what-to-do/" class="bare">https://ask.fedoraproject.org/en/question/98598/i-get-a-segmentation-fault-when-starting-synapse-on-fedora-25-what-to-do/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fedora/comments/5j31sd/synapse_on_fedora_25_fails_with_segmentation/" class="bare">https://www.reddit.com/r/Fedora/comments/5j31sd/synapse_on_fedora_25_fails_with_segmentation/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/synapse-project/+bug/1592008" class="bare">https://bugs.launchpad.net/synapse-project/+bug/1592008</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Unfotunately everyone was complaining, but no solution.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_solution">The Solution</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I figured it was synapse trying to access memory or a stream that doesn&#8217;t exist. So I checked <code>syanpse -h</code> to see what options are available. One of the options available to use <code>--display</code>. You can get synapse to successfully start by the following steps.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>check the location of the displays you have available: <code>cd /tmp/.X11-unix &amp;&amp; for x in X*; do echo ":${x#X}"; done</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>then, from the locations listed, try using any as arguments to the <code>--display</code> option.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For me, <code>synapse --display=:0</code> worked just fine.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>NB: This allows you to manually launch synapse. However, you MAY want to ensure that:</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>When you start synapse from the application menu it launches with the options you desire.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>append ` --display=:0` to the end of <code>Exec=synapse</code> in the file <code>/usr/share/applications/synapse.desktop</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You WILL need <strong>sudo</strong> access to do this. <strong>Be mindful of the space in the string you will be appending.</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>If it&#8217;s autostarted from your startup it is launched with the options you desire.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>ensure you have <strong>GNOME Tweak Tool</strong> installed. <strong>Install it using <code>sudo dnf install gnome-tweak-tool</code> or install it from the <strong>Software</strong> application</strong>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Then navigate: Tweak Tool&gt;Startup Applications&gt;➕. Search for Synapse then click "Add".</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This should suffice as a solution until a patch is made.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This has been tested on fedora 25. Provide feedback as to whether it works on other distributions that are returning</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>[INFO 10:45:12.413170] [synapse-main:266] Starting up...
[INFO 10:45:12.625883] [synapse-main:208] Binding activation to &lt;Control&gt;space
[1]    27269 segmentation fault (core dumped)  synapse</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://iamthinkking.github.io/2017/01/10/Fedora25-Synapse-and-Your-Display-Server.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://iamthinkking.github.io/2017/01/10/Fedora25-Synapse-and-Your-Display-Server.html</guid><category><![CDATA[fedora]]></category><category><![CDATA[ linux]]></category><category><![CDATA[ synapse]]></category><category><![CDATA[ launcher]]></category><category><![CDATA[ solution]]></category><category><![CDATA[ terminal]]></category><category><![CDATA[ display]]></category><category><![CDATA[ wayland]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Xorg]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christopher Lee Murray]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terminal: WiFi Password]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>As a budding Linux Engineer I have found that the command line is often a very useful tool. You can get information faster and with greater detail. Often times for the information needed, there is no app with a GUI to provide it. Knowing a decent amount of commands, improves performance and efficiency by a great deal.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One particular example of this is my constant need to retrieve the WiFi passwords of the networks I have already connected to. Of course, storing them in a file is a good way to keep them, but it is also a redundant method, due to linux systems already storing them in files.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have utilized the command line to get the desired output. However, it would be time consuming and strenuous to be typing a lengthy command multiple times per day, even if I were to press ⬆ to travel through my terminal&#8217;s history or do <code>history | grep [name of word in command here]</code> to filter the list of recently entered commands. A beautiful solution to this is simply to use the <code>alias</code> command to store frequently used commands and comand combinations. Below is the result of my contemplations. I will explain them after. It is worth mentioning that the directories/paths we are accessing requires <strong>superuser</strong> privileges, so tread carefully.</p>
</div>
<div id="app-listing" class="listingblock">
<div class="title">wifipass, on fedora25</div>
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>alias wifipass="{(sudo ls \
/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ \
| grep 'keys-') &amp;&amp; \
(sudo cat /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/keys-*)} \
| pr --column 2 -Tt"</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Fedora, the network passwords (PSK or Pre-Shared Key) is stored in separate files for each network. However, the network name (SSID, or Service Set IDentifier) is within the filename itself, prefixed by <code>keys-</code>. The first part of the command (<code>sudo ls /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ | grep 'keys-')</code>) is to retrieve the existing SSIDs, the second part of the script (<code>sudo cat /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/keys-*</code>) is to retrieve the PSKs of each network. As the directory tree is traversed the order will remain consistent, therefore the order the SSIDs are returned is the same order the PSKs will be returned.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Optional</strong>: However, the SSIDs will be listed first then the PSKs. Because of this we use <code>pr</code> to format the text into 2 columns. The <code>2</code> is the number of columns and the <code>-Tt</code> are the two options passed which omit pagination and omit the header respectively.</p>
</div>
<div id="app-listing" class="listingblock">
<div class="title">wifipass, on ubuntu16.10</div>
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>alias wifipass="sudo cat \
/etc/NetworkManager/system-connections/* \
| grep -e ssid -e psk"</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Ubuntu, all network configuration is stored inside separate files but the SSIDs are in the respective files, along with the PSKs. This allows us to retrieve what we need with a bit less hassle. Therefore, the command retrieves all the text in each file then filters for lines containing only <code>ssisd</code> and <code>psk</code>.</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Often times the information needed, there is no app with a GUI to provide it.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; Christopher Lee Murray
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>NB:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><code>|</code> is used to "pipe" output. This allows you to move the stream of an output and use it as as input stream.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>alias</code> is used to store commands that you often use to make your CLI life easier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>*</code> is the "wildcard" symbol which I will speak on more in a REGEX post later.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Should you need to store these commands permanently (to used them after every boot) then you would need to store them in your <code>~/.bashrc</code> or your <code>~/.zhrc</code> file depending on your shell/</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></description><link>https://iamthinkking.github.io/2016/12/23/Terminal-WiFi-Password.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://iamthinkking.github.io/2016/12/23/Terminal-WiFi-Password.html</guid><category><![CDATA[fedora]]></category><category><![CDATA[ ubuntu]]></category><category><![CDATA[ linux]]></category><category><![CDATA[ wifi]]></category><category><![CDATA[ password]]></category><category><![CDATA[ alias]]></category><category><![CDATA[ cli]]></category><category><![CDATA[ terminal]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Christopher Lee Murray]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>